1964年，全世界的目光都聚焦在日本——
In 1964, the eyes of the world were fixed on Japan
东京奥运会盛大开幕。
as the Olympic Games kicked off in Tokyo.
但真正抓住全球眼球的，不是奖牌，也不是盛典。
But, it wasn't the medals or parades that captured the world's attention.
而是新干线——
It was the Shinkansen,
一列划时代的高速列车，
a revolutionary high-speed train
以破纪录的速度将乘客送往日本各地。
shooting passengers across the country at record speeds.
这列子弹头列车，令全世界羡慕不已。
The bullet train was the envy of the world.
它一声枪响，引燃了一场全球竞赛：谁能成为下一个跻身高铁俱乐部的国家？
Firing the starter pistol on a global race to be the next country to enter the high-speed club.
跑在最前面的，是美国。
In pole position was the United States.
凭借雄厚的技术实力和超级大国的资源，
With its technical prowess and superpower resources,
一列纯美国血统的列车开始筹备——
work began on an all-American train
目标是让新干线望尘莫及。
that would leave the Shinkansen in the dust.
最高时速156英里（约251公里），几乎是当今最快列车的两倍。
Hitting a top speed of 156 mph, nearly double today's fastest speed.
然而，子弹头列车在日本成了国家象征，60年过去了，
But, while the bullet train became a national icon in Japan, 60 years on,
美国却仍在为建造第一条高铁线路苦苦挣扎。
the US is still struggling to build its first high-speed rail line.
这是一个关于壮志未酬的故事，
This is a story of failed ambition,
但它留下的遗产，
but with a legacy
至今对美国铁路举足轻重。
that to this day remains of critical importance to rail in the United States.
这就是美国尝试建造子弹头列车时所发生的一切。
This is what happens when America tried to build a bullet train.
约翰逊总统向国会领袖们致以祝贺，
President Johnson has some words of congratulations
感谢他们
for congressional leaders
推动税收法案在两院顺利通过。
who spurred the tax bill through both houses.
林登·B·约翰逊总统是一个有着宏大愿景的人。
President Lyndon B. Johnson was a man with a vision.
1963年就任后，
When he took office in 1963,
他立志将美国
he set out to transform America
打造成"伟大社会"。
into the Great Society.
他推行的一系列
The policies he introduced
政策，旨在纠正美国社会各层面的积弊，
sought to right wrongs in every part of American life,
交通运输也不例外。
including transport.
美国开发出了举世无双的先进交通工具，
The US had developed the most technologically advanced vehicles in and out of the world,
但有一个重大例外。
but with one major exception.
>> >> 我们有飞行速度达到音速三倍的飞机。
>> >> We have airplanes which fly three times faster than sound.
我们有绕火星运行的电视摄像机，
We have television cameras that are orbiting Mars,
但城镇之间的大众交通，和30年前一样，
but we have the same tired and inadequate mass transportation
依然陈旧落后，毫无长进。
between our towns and cities that we had 30 years ago.
如果你没有汽车，在国内出行简直是一场折磨。
If you didn't have a car, getting around the country was a slog.
更糟糕的是，仅仅20年前还是美国交战国的日本，
And to make it worse, Japan, a country the US was at war with
如今凭借最新机车技术引领着世界。
just 20 years earlier, was now leading the world with its latest locomotive.
>> [snorts] >> 子弹或许很快，但雄鹰更快。
>> [snorts] >> A bullet might be fast, but an eagle is faster.
1965年，LBJ签署了《高速地面交通法案》。
In 1965, LBJ signed the High-Speed Ground Transportation Act.
目标很简单：
Its goal was simple,
支持美国高速铁路网络的
to back the research and development
研究与开发。
of a high-speed train network in the US.
其实，这并不是美国第一次涉足高铁领域。
Although this wasn't America's first foray into high-speed rail.
让我们听听历史学家罗伯特·霍尔茨韦斯的讲述。
Here's historian Robert Holzweiss to tell us more.
上世纪50年代末，纽约中央铁路在俄亥俄州搞了一个演示项目。
The New York Central Railroad in the late 1950s did a demonstration project in Ohio.
他们把两台航空喷气发动机
It mounted two airline jet engines
架在一节铁路柴油车（RDC）
on the top of what we call a rail diesel car
的顶上。
or an RDC.
就是一节普通的客车车厢。
It's just one passenger car.
然后在一段笔直平坦的轨道上跑出了170多英里（约274公里）的时速。
And they went 170-something mph across a straight flat piece of track.
测试地点是精心挑选的——
The area that was chosen to do this was purposely done.
地势平坦笔直，
It was flat and straight,
基础设施状况极佳。
and the infrastructure was in very good condition.
我不认为
I don't think
有人真的认真考虑过
there was any serious consideration
把这个方案变成
of making these an actual
实际的载客运输方式。
um way of transporting people.
好在还有一些没那么疯狂的尝试，在推动高铁走向现实。
Fortunately, there were other less insane attempts to get high-speed rail up and running.
克莱本·佩尔参议员登场了。
Enter Senator Claiborne Pell.
1962年，他提出了"佩尔计划"。
In 1962, he had developed the Pell Plan.
这一计划呼吁重振铁路网络，服务于东北走廊沿线高度密集的城市群——
It called for a revitalized rail network serving the highly dense cluster of cities
也就是我们今天所说的东北走廊。
along the Northeast Corridor, a network we now call the Northeast Corridor.
随着人们从城市涌向郊区，
As people moved from the cities to the suburbs,
数以百万计的人开车上路，
millions took to the roads
开启了通勤时代。
to begin commuting.
但道路很快就堵死了，另一套解决方案迫在眉睫。
But, as those roads quickly clogged up, another solution was needed.
州际公路对美国文化影响深远，
Interstate highways were a big impact on the US culture,
我们本质上是一个汽车文化的国家。
and we were are a car culture.
但发展大众交通的呼声，确实也在一步步向前推进。
And there was definitely a movement forward to get into more mass transportation.
后来被称为东北走廊的这条线路，
What became known as the Northeast Corridor,
当时归宾夕法尼亚铁路所有，
then owned by the Pennsylvania Railroad,
成了最理想的改造目标。
was a prime target for that.
这条线路早已实现电气化——自1930年代起便是如此，
It was already electrified, had been since 1930s,
非常适合进一步发展为连接美国经济首都纽约
and it was ripe for further development into a more high-speed transportation corridor
与政治首都华盛顿特区的高速交通走廊。
between the economic capital of the US, New York,
and the political capital, Washington, D.C.
随着约翰逊高铁梦逐渐成形，
As Johnson's high-speed dream began to take shape,
它最终落地为
it did so in the form
佩尔参议员针对东北走廊提出的方案。
of Senator Pell's plan for the Northeast Corridor.
该法案资助了两个试点项目。
The bill sponsored two test projects.
第一个就是这列——巴德公司涡轮列车（Turbo Train）。
The first was this, the Turbo train.
采用电力驱动加柴油涡轮引擎，
Using an electric engine and a diesel-powered turbine,
运行于纽约
it would run between New York
与波士顿之间。
and Boston.
第二个方案服务于至关重要的纽约至华盛顿路线，
The second scheme would serve the crucial New York to Washington route,
而正是这个方案，
and it was this
对美国铁路产生了最为深远的影响。
that would go on to have the most lasting impacts on US rail.
好了，说到这个故事，我们得回到那个遥远的年代——
Now, we're going way back into the mists of time with this story
那时候，人们只能用极为原始的技术工作。
when they had to work with very primitive technology.
我这儿就有个例子。
I have an example of it here.
叫做纸和笔。
It's called pen and paper.
这是我从当地博物馆借来的，
I borrowed these from a local museum,
但没人真的知道
but no one really knows
怎么用。
how they work.
好在，在今天这个开明的时代，
Fortunately, in today's enlightened age,
我们可以依赖更先进的技术，
we can rely on more advanced technology
比如Odoo。
such as Odoo.
Odoo是一个一体化的企业管理平台，
Odoo is an all-in-one business management platform
把经营企业中所有繁琐的事务
that takes all the painful stuff about running a business
都化繁为简。
and makes it a breeze.
别说建一条新铁路了，光是运营B1M就有一大堆后台工作：
Forget building a new railway,
追收款、签合同、排人手、管HR，诸如此类。
running the B1M comes with a ton of back office work,
chasing invoices, signing contracts, scheduling resources, HR, you name it.
但现在这些我都能在Odoo里一站式搞定，
But, now I can do all of that within Odoo
因为他们把45个应用整合进了一个高效的生态系统。
because they've taken 45 apps and brought them all into one efficient ecosystem.
各模块无缝联通，
Everything communicates seamlessly,
Odoo甚至能自动处理那些看似微不足道的手动任务——
and Odoo can even automate manual tasks
直到你在复制数据时少打了个零，
that seem trivial until you miss a zero off when copying data across
然后一切就彻底脱轨。
and then everything goes off the rails.
你可以根据自身需求量身定制，
You can tailor everything to your specific needs,
而且扩展性很强。
plus it's scalable.
所以你可以从小处起步，随着业务增长再逐步添加应用。
So, you can start off small and add apps as your business grows.
最棒的是，你的第一个应用完全免费，终身使用，
But, the best part is that your first app is completely free for life,
还包含无限技术支持
and that includes unlimited support
和托管服务。
and hosting.
你所要做的，就是选好第一个应用，上手试试。
All you got to do is choose your first app and give it a try.
扫描屏幕上的二维码，
You can do that by scanning the QR code on screen
或点击简介中的链接，
or clicking the link in the description
今天就开始吧。
to get started today.
好了，你们继续看视频，我来研究研究这玩意儿怎么用。
Now, I'm going to let you guys watch the rest of the video while I'll figure out what to do with this.
如果你要建一条高铁线路，
Now, if you're building a high-speed rail line,
有几个关键因素
there are a few things
必须考虑周全。
you've got to take into consideration.
首先，速度越快，任何颠簸和震动都会被成倍放大，
First off, traveling fast means you'll feel any bump or jolt far more than lower speeds.
所以轨道必须焊接固定，
So, your track needs to be welded into place
防止列车和乘客被震得七零八落。
to stop the trains and the passengers being shaken to pieces.
列车碾过钢轨接缝时那种熟悉的"咔嗒"声，将彻底消失。
That familiar click-clack sounds as the train passes over different sets of rails is gone.
其次，要尽可能减少一切降速因素。
Secondly, you want as few things to slow you down as possible.
排在首位的就是弯道。
Top of that list are corners.
沿线每一处曲线
Any curves along the route
都必须尽量平缓、舒展。
need to be as shallow and gentle as possible.
高速过弯时，离心力会将列车向外甩。
Going round a corner at high speed means the centrifugal force will throw the train outwards.
因此，轨道的倾角——即轨道超高——必须相应抬高，
So, the angle or can't of the track needs to be raised
以平衡作用在钢轨上的载荷。
to balance the load applied on the rails.
最后，还需要稳定可靠的电力供应。
Finally, you'll also need a reliable power supply.
>> >> 对于电力列车，电能由头顶的架空导线提供，这套系统叫做接触网。
>> >> For electric trains, that's supplied by the overhead wires known as a catenary.
高速行驶时，受电弓会发生抖动，与导线失去接触。
At high speeds, the pantograph would bounce and lose contact with the wire.
所以他们不得不改变导线的架设方式，
And so, they had to change the way the the wire was strung,
同时也改变了受电弓的工作方式——
and they uh also had to change the way the pantograph operated
从原来的三角形结构改为V形，
from a sort of a triangular shape to a V-shape,
以保持张力，确保受电弓始终与导线紧密接触。
and to keep tension on it and keep it in contact with the wire.
1966年，一段21英里长的试验轨道
In 1966, work began on upgrading a 21-mile stretch of track
开始升级改造，用于在整条线路完工前对首批车厢
which would be used to test the first cars
进行测试。
before work on the whole line was complete.
测试区选在新泽西州，
The test area was was going to be in New Jersey,
那里早已有大量平直轨道，
where it was already a significant amount of flat and straight track,
与十年前纽约中央铁路在俄亥俄州所选条件如出一辙。
just like in the Ohio example with the New York Central a decade earlier.
他们希望确保所有环节运转正常，
And so, they wanted to make sure that everything worked properly
再从那里向外拓展、
before they built out from there
推进基础设施改造。
and improved the infrastructure.
>> >> 但这不过是简单的部分，
>> >> But, that was the easy bit,
没过多久，
and it wasn't long
整个项目就开始脱轨了。
before the project started going off the rails.
当时，整条线路归宾夕法尼亚铁路所有。
At the time, the whole line was owned by the Pennsylvania Railroad.
协议是这样的：美国政府出资升级轨道，
The deal was that the US government would pay for the upgrade of the track
宾夕法尼亚铁路
while the PRR
负责采购列车。
would fork out for the trains.
但这并没有给宾夕法尼亚铁路多少自主空间。
But, that didn't exactly give them a free hand.
由于项目时间极为紧迫，宾夕法尼亚铁路希望购买
Because of the project's short time frames, the PRR wanted to buy trains
时速120英里（约193公里）的列车。
that would run at 120 mph.
这种列车制造起来相对简单，
They'd be fairly straightforward to build
也不需要原方案中那些耗资巨大的轨道升级。
and wouldn't need all the expensive track upgrades that were proposed.
但在政府看来，这完全偏离了初衷。
But, for the government, that completely missed the point.
这不仅仅是对现有服务的小打小闹，
This wasn't just about a modest upgrade in service,
这本应是
this was supposed to be America's
美国跻身高铁头等舱的入场券。
ticket into the first class lounge of high-speed train service.
目标是让子弹头列车130英里（约209公里）的时速显得不值一提。
It was supposed to make the 130 mph of the bullet train look half-cocked.
这是一条红线：列车时速必须达到150英里（约241公里）。
This was a red line. The trains had to hit 150 mph.
于是，他们拿出了这个方案——都会班车（Metroliner）。
So, this is what they came up with, the Metroliner.
我知道你在想什么——
Now, I know what you're thinking.
这哪里像高铁的样子。
It doesn't look very high-speed.
涡轮列车看起来像喷气式飞机，
The Turbo train looked more like a jet plane than a train.
子弹头列车造型酷炫、气势十足。
The bullet train looked and sounded cool.
都会班车看起来就是一列普通火车，因为它本来就是。
The Metroliner just kind of looked like a normal train because it was.
工期太紧，根本没时间开发原型车。
Deadlines were so tight, there was no time to develop a prototype.
于是宾夕法尼亚铁路买入一批现有车厢，
So, the PRR bought a series of existing train cars
开始大规模改造，
and began extensive upgrades
将它们升级为高速列车。
to transform them into high-speed units.
车厢内的电气系统被彻底拆除，换上了全新的高速传动系统。
The cars' electrics were stripped out and replaced with a new high-speed gearing system.
每节车厢都安装了新型受电弓，以确保与架空电线的连接更加可靠。
Each car was fitted with a new graph to create a more reliable connection to the overhead power lines.
悬挂系统采用了两种方式。
Two types of suspension were used.
螺旋弹簧承载列车自重，
Coil springs were fitted to take the weight of the train
空气弹簧则用于补偿乘客重量的变化。
and air springs were used to compensate for the weight of the passengers.
车上还配备了全新的计算机速度控制系统，驾驶员只需拨动旋钮设定目标速度，
A new computerized speed control system was fitted,
加减速全部由车载计算机自动完成。
which allowed the driver to set the train's speed by a dial
and then leave any braking or accelerating
加减速全部由车载计算机自动完成。
to be done by the train's on-board computer.
与贝尔实验室合作，
A partnership with Bell Laboratories
列车甚至搭载了一项颠覆性的新发明——
even equipped the trains with a radical new invention
让乘客在美国任何地方都能打电话：
that allowed people to place a call anywhere in the US,
车载蜂窝电话系统。
the cell phone.
轨道沿线埋设了感应线圈，
The route was marked with coils,
列车经过时，
which, as the train passed over,
手机信号会自动切换到
switched the phone signal to the local frequency
当前所在区域（即"小区"）的频率。
or cell that it was traveling through.
乘坐美铁都会班车，您可以在用早餐时从容处理事务。
On Amtrak's Metroliner service, you can spread out over breakfast.
这项服务显然是针对
This was definitely targeted
商务人士和需要在旅途中舒适办公的人群——
toward businessmen and people
既要安静，又要便于沟通。
who needed to work as they traveled in comfort
and quiet and also the communication.
列车被设计成高速、
And they were designed as a high-speed,
舒适、配备空调、
very comfortable, air-conditioned,
内饰精良的商务车厢。
uh very well-appointed interior with club cars.
列车在外形上也并非毫无流线型设计。
The trains weren't completely devoid of streamlining.
车头增加了新的前端面板，但更多的改动被认为没有必要。
A new front panel was added to the cars, but any more than this was considered unnecessary.
这也与列车的运营方式有关。
It would also clash with how the trains were to be used.
日本零系列车被设计为固定12节编组运行，而都会班车追求的是灵活性。
The Japanese Zero series was designed to be deployed in standardized 12-car sets,
but the Metroliner was designed for flexibility.
每节车厢自带动力，
Each car was self-powered
一端设有驾驶室，
with a cab at one end.
两两成对组合，
These were grouped in pairs of two
并可根据客流量增减编组。
and a train could be made longer or shorter based on the number of passengers using that service.
他们希望能够
They wanted to be able
根据实际客流调整
to adjust the size of the train to the passenger load
列车长度，而不是
rather than having an inflexible back and forth,
让一列固定编组的列车来回跑、来回跑、
back and forth, back and forth
来回跑，一半座位 >> >> 都空着。
train riding with only half the seats >> >> filled.
就这样，1967年初，新列车的测试工作正式展开。
So, in early 1967, testing began on the new trains.
铁路运输新纪元，由此开启。
The dawn of a new era in rail transportation.
在测试中，
In trials,
都会班车轻松突破了
they smashed the 150 mph target
交通运输部设定的150英里目标，
set by the Department of Transportation,
但前方的线路上，麻烦已在等候。
but there was trouble on the line ahead.
不只是
You see, it wasn't just
列车本身被逼到了极限——
the trains that were made to run at breakneck speed. The whole program was being pushed to its limits.
整个项目都在超负荷运转。
催生这个项目的法案于1965年签署生效。
The bill that gave birth to the project was signed into law in 1965.
与宾夕法尼亚
Negotiations with the Pennsylvania
铁路的谈判一直延续到1966年，
Railroad continued until 1966
而列车原定于1967年
and the train was due to go into service
10月投入运营。
in October 1967.
日本用了整整6年规划和建造新干线，
It took Japan 6 years to plan and build the Shinkansen,
而美国却妄想在短短25个月内复制同样的成就。
but the US was hoping to do the same in just 25 months.
结果，技术问题接踵而至，越积越多。
As a result, technical issues began to pile up.
为迎接都会班车投入运营，50节车厢被提前下单订购。
50 carriages were ordered in anticipation of the Metroliner entering service.
这是十多年来最大规模的
It was the biggest
新车订单，
order of new cars in over a decade
而巴德公司只有17个月
and the Budd company had just 17 months
来完成制造。
to build them.
交付的车辆问题重重——
The vehicles that were delivered were riddled with bugs,
牵引系统故障、
broken traction systems,
发动机起火、高速行驶时车门飞脱。
engine fires, and doors that flew off at high speeds.
都会班车的开通时间被迫推迟至1969年，
The opening of the Metroliner service was delayed until 1969,
但即便如此，大多数问题依然悬而未决。
but even then most issues weren't resolved.
1969年至1970年间，近半数都会班车因技术故障停运待修。
Between 1969 and 1970, nearly half the Metroliner cars were out of service
because of technical faults.
但只要列车能跑到150英里每小时，不就算大功告成了吗？
But surely, as long as the trains were traveling at 150 mph, it was mission accomplished, right?
并没有。在大部分运营时间里，都会班车的平均时速只有110英里（约177公里）。
Well, no. For most of its service, the average Metroliner speed was just 110 mph.
早期测试车辆所用的那段试验轨道，条件得天独厚。
The test track used for the early cars provided exceptionally favorable conditions.
>> >> 笔直平坦，还带着轻微的下坡坡度。
>> >> It was straight and flat with a slight downward slope.
华盛顿至纽约
The rest of the track between Washington and New York
之间的其余线路按计划完成了升级，
was upgraded as planned,
但能做到的毕竟有限。
but there was only so much that could be done.
说到底，列车跑的还是100年前的那条老路。
Ultimately, the trains were still running on the same track and routes as 100 years ago.
这条线路从来不是为高铁专门建造的，而这，将成为它永远的阿喀琉斯之踵。
It was not purposely built for high-speed rail and that is going to be an Achilles' heel.
打造一条高铁线路需要方方面面
There's a lot
的条件，如果让我从头另辟新线，
of things that need to go into making a high-speed line
我会把它建得笔直，
and if you pull that out and put it somewhere else,
建得平坦。
I would build it straight, I would build it flat.
无论是设备
I would build it with the most contemporary
还是周边基础设施，
modern technology as far as equipment,
我都会采用最现代、最先进的技术。
but also as the infrastructure surrounding it.
日本从来没有这个烦恼。
You see, Japan never had that problem.
新干线动工时，
When work began on the Shinkansen,
日本大多数列车
most of Japan's trains ran
跑的是窄轨线路，
on narrow-gauge track
这些线路蜿蜒穿行于崎岖山地，根本不适合高速行驶。
that could navigate the twists and turns of its mountainous landscape.
换句话说，那些轨道永远无法改造成高铁线路。
In other words, track that would never be suitable for a high-speed train.
与其在旧线上修修补补，日本选择从零开始，建造一条全新的专用线路——
Instead of upgrading, an entirely new purpose-built route was constructed,
即日语中所称的"新干线"，也就是新的主干线。
a new main line or Shinkansen in Japanese.
美国在一次性技术突破上向来得心应手——原子弹、太空竞赛莫不如此。
The US had become great at singular technological breakthroughs, the atom bomb, the space race.
高铁也被视为
High-speed rail was considered
这类"登月式大项目"之一：
as another one of these moonshot projects,
一个技术难题，
a technical problem
只要集中全国最聪明的头脑就能攻克。
that could be solved by putting the country's best and brightest minds on it.
但事实并非如此。
But it wasn't about that.
它考验的是日复一日、分毫不差的细致规划。
It was about the long, hard yards of meticulous planning.
正如日本所证明的：高铁的成功不是技术革命，而是行政管理的胜利。
As Japan learned, high-speed rail wasn't a technical revolution, it was a triumph of bureaucracy.
都会班车终究是短命的。
Ultimately, the Metroliner was short-lived.
1969年开始运营后，技术问题被逐步解决，但代价极为高昂。
After service began in 1969, technical issues were slowly addressed, but at huge cost.
1971年，美铁接管了整个网络，并迅速着手寻找替代方案。
In 1971, Amtrak took over the network and quickly started looking for a replacement.
各型车辆
Various cars
经过翻修后
were overhauled and repurposed
被重新投入使用，都会班车这一品牌
and the Metroliner brand was kept alive
一直延续到2006年。
until 2006.
但最初的服务早在1976年便开始逐步退出，1981年彻底停运。
But the original service began to be phased out back in 1976 and was ended completely in 1981.
巴德涡轮列车也未能赢得多少荣光。
The Budd Turbo train didn't achieve much glory either.
由于高度依赖柴油，它在1970年代能源危机中遭受重创，1976年停止运营。
Heavily reliant on diesel, it was hit by the 1970s energy crisis and service ended in 1976.
美国至今仍在与同样的问题苦苦周旋。
The US is still struggling with this problem today.
加利福尼亚高铁正在吸取
California high-speed rail is learning the lessons
都会班车的教训，
from Metroliner by carving
沿西海岸另辟专用路线，
out its own route along the West Coast,
但也因此深陷土地征收这一棘手问题的泥潭。
but as a result of that, it's become tangled up in the thorny issue of land acquisition.
前景谈不上乐观，
It's hardly encouraging,
但《高速地面交通法案》确实留下了一份值得骄傲的遗产，
but the High-Speed Act does have a legacy
而这也是佩尔参议员早就预见到的。
it can be proud of and one that Senator Pell saw coming all along.
都会班车或许
You see, the Metroliner may
不及日本同行那般出色，
not have lived up to its Japanese counterpart,
但出人意料的是，
but against all the odds,
人们真的喜欢它。
people loved it.
都会班车项目，至少在早期，运营得非常非常好，吸引了大批乘客。
The Metroliner program, at least in the early years, worked very, very well and attracted a lot of ridership.
1973年的石油危机，
The oil shock of 1973 definitely
让许多人开始重新
gave people second thoughts
审视拥有两辆车或长途驾车的必要性，
about owning two cars or driving long distances,
尤其是当这样的铁路服务就摆在眼前时。
especially when a service like this was available.
事实上，各铁路公司
In fact, railroads were scrambling
和当时的美铁
and Amtrak at the time was scrambling
都在四处奔走，
to find equipment
拼命寻找能够满足旅客出行需求的车辆。
to be able to serve the traveling public.
在美国大部分地区，铁路并不是切实
Across most of the US, rail isn't a viable
可行的大众出行方式，
mass transport option,
但尽管如此，
but despite that,
东北走廊铁路网已成为国家级关键基础设施。
the Northeast Corridor rail network has become a critical piece of national infrastructure.
每天有80万人乘坐这条网络上的2000列列车出行。
800,000 people ride this network every day across 2,000 trains.
它所服务的地区贡献了美国20%的GDP和30%的就业岗位。
The region it serves generates 20% of America's GDP and 30% of its jobs.
或许线路老旧失修、亟待整改，但客流依然旺盛——这是两回事。
It may be creaking and in need of repair, but that's in spite of its ridership, not because of it.
归根结底，佩尔关于铁路是这一地区交通主力的判断是正确的。
Ultimately, Pell's analysis of rail being the mainstay of transport in this region was correct.
而为此，我们要感谢那列默默无闻的都会班车。
And for that, we have the humble Metroliner to thank.
本视频由Odoo赞助制作。
This video was made possible by Odoo.
点击下方链接了解更多。
Check them out at the link below.
大家如果能花时间
And remember that it massively
关注一下我们的视频赞助商，
helps us to keep producing these videos
对我们持续制作
when you guys take the time to go and check out
内容真的帮助很大。
our video sponsors.
一如既往，如果
And as always, guys,
你喜欢这期视频，
if you enjoyed this video
想要获取更多
and you want to get more
来自建筑领域权威视频频道的
from the definitive video channel
内容，请确保你已订阅B1M。
for construction, make sure you're subscribed to the B1M.